<ecopedia priority="3" icon="CivicObjectComponent">
<section type="header">Government Guide - short version</section>

 <section>
 
 This part is intended as a short HowTo on what to do in these roles
 
<b>Citizens</b>
  - read Server Rules and Federal Law
  - you can vote in elections and candidate for government titles
 
<b>Federal President:</b>
  - how did you get this title?
  
  
<section type="header">executive</section>
  
<b>Prime Minister:</b>
  -  elected by all citizens
  -  one week terms
  -  can only veto senate laws with 6 or fewer “yes” votes. No vetoing SC laws
  -  full control over treasury and how to spend the tax money
  -  responsible for government goals (meteor, infrastructure, building code)
  -  can appoint Secretaries to help
  
<b>Deputy Prime Minister:</b>
  -  appointed by the Prime Minister
  -  one week terms
  -  becomes Prime Minister if Prime Minister goes inactive
  -  also control over treasury spending to help Prime Minister
  -  assists the Prime Minister in the government business
  
<b>Chancellor of the Federal University:</b>
  -  appointed by the Prime Minister
  -  
  
<b>Director of the Federal Bank:</b>
  -  appointed by Prime Minister
  -  term alongside the Prime Minister
  -  no other offices
  -  only one who can mint currencies
  -  no minting Euro into government funds, the Federal Bank has its own, independent budget
  -  always ensure enough Euros are in stock for trading Land Claim Papers
  -  give out loans to citizen-led banks or citizens, if noone wants to bank
  -  mint Donation Receipts for the rest of the government to use
  -  mint shares for companies and oversee the stock market for these shares
  

<b>Federal Secretary:</b>
  -  appointed by Prime Minister
  -  term until appointment ends
  -  usually gets a budget from the Prime Minister
  -  helps the Government in one specific task (e.g. Roads, Property, Meteor, …)
  

<section type="header">legislative/state officials</section>

<b>Mayor of Unica:</b>
  -  elected by the citizens of Unica
  -  one week terms

<b>Governor/Mayor:</b>
  -  one per district
  -  elected by citizens in their district
  -  proposes, votes and abolishes general laws (not for/against specific players)
  -  decides wages for government
  -  no messing with single players
  -  one week terms
  
<b>Lieutenant Governor/Deputy Mayor:</b>
  -  one per district
  -  elected by citizens in their district
  -  proposes, votes and abolishes general laws (not for/against specific players)
  -  decides wages for government
  -  no messing with single players
  -  one week terms

<section type="header">judiciary</section>

<b>Federal Judge:</b>
  -  3 in total
  -  appointed by Prime Minister
  -  creates “rulings” (laws ONLY for/against specific player/fix group of players)
  -  term for life (until Abandoned/step down)

<b>Attorney General:</b>
  -  3 in total
  -  appointed by Prime Minister
  -  creates “rulings” (laws ONLY for/against specific player/fix group of players)
  -  term for life (until Abandoned/step down)


  </section>



<section type="header">Government Guide - the long version</section>
<section type="header">The Government of White Tiger</section>
<section>
The government system of White Tiger is set up by the Game Masters before the citizens join the server. This includes the setup of a constitution and several districts, titles and laws. These make up the framework of the server and can therefore not be changed or abolished by citizens. 
The government powers are divided between different roles. These roles can be broadly split into a legislative and an executive branch.
</section>
<section type="header">The legislative</section>
<section>
The legislative branch on the federal level is represented by the Senate.
Each state of the world elects two of its citizens to become their Governor and Lieutenant Governor and to represent them in the senate. For Unica, these positions are called Mayor and Deputy Mayor instead, as it's a city state.
Senators have the power to propose and vote on general laws, which are discussed and decided upon in the senate. These laws are not restricted to the possibilities of Eco’s law system, but they are valid according to their intention conveyed by the law’s text.
Senators are therefore only limited by their imagination when writing laws and as long as the laws do not violate the constitution, every general law is allowed. In essence, the senate decides how the citizens should act, what to allow and what to forbid, which actions to subsidy and which to tax.
They can also alter 
The supreme court consists of the Chief Judge and two other Judges. They oversee the senate and have the power to repeal any law. The Federal Judge candidates are first appointed by the Prime Minister, which enables them to candidate in a Supreme Court Election. The senate then votes on this election and confirms the candidates into the supreme court.
The Federal Judges hold this power until they step down voluntarily or join the Abandoned demographic.
The Federal Judges are allowed to abolish laws that the senate passed, as well as executing laws that are considered “rulings”, meaning they decide exactly one case or help/punish exactly one player or fixed player group.
Furthermore, the Federal Judge has the power to remove any government official, except the other Federal Judges, from their offices.
While both the senate and supreme court have the technical power to propose, vote on and abolish every law, they are not allowed to vote on each other's elections.
The senate may not:
  -  create a law that only rules over a specific case or punishes/subsidizes one or a fixed group of citizens. 
  -  vote in an election that a member of the supreme court started
  -  abolish a law that was written by the supreme court
The supreme court may not:
  -  create laws that affect the general population. They are only allowed “rulings” that affect specific cases such as “Player XYZ is not allowed to trade until the 6th day”.
  -  vote in an election that a member of the senate started
The Prime Minister may not:
  -  veto any law that is in election by a member of the Supreme Court, they are only allowed to veto law proposals of the senate.
  -  veto any law that has more than 6 senators supporting it. Only laws that have 6 or fewer senators supporting it may be vetoed.
</section>
<section type="header">The executive branch</section>
<section>
The executive branch of the government consists of different roles. The Prime Minister is the leader of the executive branch and it’s their responsibility to ensure that the different tasks of the government are fulfilled. Their funding comes out of the treasury and they are elected by a direct vote.
The Deputy Prime Minister succeeds the Prime Minister if they become inactive and helps them in fulfilling the governmental duties. They have almost as much power as the Prime Minister and are also elected in a direct vote.
The Mayor of the Federal Capital is the leader of the Capital. Their job is ensuring that the Capital becomes a great city by constructing roads, providing power and improving houses. They are not funded out of the treasury, instead the sales of plots inside the Capital go into the “Federal Capital” bank account, which the Mayor manages. To access other forms of income, they have to discuss with the other government members to find suitable taxation methods. Like Prime Minister and Deputy Prime Minister, they are elected in a direct vote.
The Director of the Federal Bank is appointed by the Prime Minister but is not a subordinate of the executive branch of the government. They represent the Federal Bank, which is the only institution in the world that mints Dollars, the global currency. They have incredible financial power by having the only store where a Land Claim Paper can be exchanged into 100 Dollars, and back. Their job is to ensure the wellbeing of the economy by controlling the minting of new Dollars and by giving out loans to private, citizen-led banks. 
The minted Dollars do not go into the treasury, but into the Federal Bank account, and the budgeting of the government and the Federal Bank are separate. The government taxes 4% of the minted amount, so 20$ per 500$ minting action.
The Director of the Federal Bank also mints Emission Permits. One Emission Permit allows a citizen to pollute 0.001 PPM of CO2 into the Air. Emission Permits are only allowed to be exchanged into Dollars and may not be traded for other items. They can be freely traded between players using Currency Exchanges.
To handle their tasks better, the Prime Minister can appoint various Secretaries and assign tasks and budgets for them. These are paid out of the treasury.
All these roles require a lot of dedication and time to fulfill, which leads to citizens in government roles often being unable to do their professions to earn money. Thus, government members get a guaranteed wage, even if retired. As a special boon, the Prime Minister also gets an Ecko Statue to boost their room value.
</section>
<section type="header">The judiciary</section>
<section>



</section>
<section type="header">Government duties</section>
<section>
The government as a whole has a lot of duties that have to be fulfilled. These are not-negotiable and duties being neglected or officials not faithfully executing their offices can lead to removal from office by the Game Masters. Some of these duties are:
<b>(1)</b> Ensure the survival of the citizens and the planet by preventing any disasters from happening.
<b>(2)</b> Build an aesthetic Capital and Monument. If there is no monument this cycle, monumental government buildings replace it.
<b>(3)</b> Build Federal Highways to connect the world. Give clear directives in terms of building layout and materials.
<b>(4)</b> Enforce the building code as defined in <b>§3</b>
<b>(5)</b> Pay every government member their wage 
Fulfilling the duties of the government takes a lot of time and effort. To motivate people to take up and execute a government title, financing for both wages and projects must be ensured. As a result, the government needs to tap into different revenue sources. The tax burden on White Tiger is often a lot higher than on vanilla servers, since many huge projects and the time of 10+ people to do them have to be financed through them. These taxes are protected by server rules and the government is authorized to prosecute and punish tax evasion with all available methods. Especially the Computer Lab is extremely costly to create, and any government that does not immediately prioritize this task and the required taxation early on will not survive.
</section>
<section type="header">Tax examples</section>
<section>
The following list of taxation methods is not exhaustive but can be used for ideas. The different pros and cons of these methods have to be evaluated by the government to choose the most suitable method of revenue generation.
  -  Sales Tax
  -  Income Tax
  -  Wealth Tax
  -  Property Tax
  -  Air Pollution Tax
  -  Tailing Creation Tax
  -  Tax on invested labor
  -  Tax on the production of certain items
  -  Tax per hour played to mimic running costs
  -  Tax for providing utilities such as power and water/sewage collection
  -  Tax on abandonment/seizing and resale of abandoned property
</section>
</ecopedia>